Guide to the Committee on the Civil War Memorial, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Committee on the Civil War Memorial, Yale University, records
1909-1915
RU 529
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The records consist of correspondence, reports, and clippings documenting the activities of the Yale Committee on the Civil War Memorial.
Yale University. Committee on the Civil War Memorial
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports, and clippings documenting the activities of the Yale Committee on the Civil War Memorial.
War memorials; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Yale University. Committee on the Civil War Memorial
- Minutes, 1909-1915; Accession 1938-A-005
  General note
  See: RU 153, ACCN 1937-A-003, Box 1
- Correspondence, 1910-1912; Accession 1991-A-057
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence between the members of the committee involved issues such as placement of the memorial, sketches for its completion and the inscription. Much discussion is given over to the placement and wording of the inscription, especially concerning the title of the War. The miscellaneous correspondence is involved mostly with the researching of names, both North and South, for the memorial.
  - Correspondence
    - Bacon, Henry, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Baldwin, Simeon E., 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everts, Allen W., 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - French, Daniel C., 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gordon, W. W., 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Howland, Henry E., 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - McClung, Lee, 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Polk, Frank L., 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Russell, Talcott H., 1912-1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1910-1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Strong, Charles H., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Wright, Henry P., 1910-1913 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1909-1917, n.d (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Committee Reports, 1911-1912 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Memorial Inscriptions, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - News Clippings, 1910, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)